(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
いつも迷惑ばかりかけるけど
I always cause you nothing but trouble, but
いつも散々困らせちゃうけど
I always make things so difficult for you, but
それでも隣にいてくれる
Even so, you still stay by my side
君のそばにずっと
By your side, forever
Watch me!
曖昧な言葉じゃ
With vague words,
真面目な君には伝わらない
it won't get through to someone serious like you
頑丈なそのハートを
That sturdy heart of yours...
覗いてみたい
I want to peer inside
融かしてみたい
I want to melt it
そんな時こんな魔法はどうかな？
At times like this, how about a magic like this?
何が出るかな？
What will come out?
やっちゃえ！
Do it!
せーの！
Ready, set...
わ！わ！わ！
Wa! Wa! Wa!
あやふやだって
Even if it's vague,
いいの！いいの！
it's okay! It's okay!
Witch One とびきり
Witch One! The outstanding...
Watch me do magic
あらら想像以上の展開
Oh my, a turn of events beyond my imagination
もう止められないのよ
I can't stop it anymore
ごめんなさい
I'm sorry
溢れる想いで空回り
Spinning my wheels with overflowing thoughts
振りかけるhappyなイメージ
Sprinkling a happy image,
で振り回すfancyなマジック
and swinging around fancy magic
また君に
You'll likely
くどくど言われちゃうけどほら
nag me again, but look!
こんなday by dayがいい
I love this kind of day by day
あの日から
Ever since that day,
falling in love with you
I've been falling in love with you
変わらないから
Because it won't change,
ずっとonly you
you'll always be my only one
だからほら
So, look,
うだうだしてる場合じゃないの
this is no time to be hesitating!
掴めハッピーエンディング
Let's grab a happy ending!
いつまでも
Forever and ever,
隣で笑っていたいのよ
I want to be laughing by your side!
いつも
I was always
仲間はずれで
left out,
ひとりぼっちの毎日
living a lonely life every day
そんな私の前に
But then, in front of me...
現れた君は
...you appeared
同じ寂しさを
You were carrying
抱えている
the same loneliness
とてもとても
A very, very
優しい人
kind person
今も心配事は多いけど
I still have many worries, but
もう私も君もひとりじゃない
neither I nor you are alone anymore
おかしくていとしいこの日々が
May these strange and precious days
ずっと続きますように
continue forever.
飛ばせ happy なイメージ
Send off a happy image!
とびきりのファンシーなマジック
The ultimate fancy magic!
また君にくどくど言われそうだけれど
It seems you'll complain to me again, but...
そんなテイク・バイ・テイクがいい
such a 'take-by-take' is fine.
あの日から falling love with you
Since that day, I've been falling in love with you.
気づいて欲しいの love with you
I want you to notice, love with you.
だからこそウダウダしてる場合じゃないの
That's why this is no time to be dilly-dallying.
次はどんなプランニング
What kind of planning next?
そしてまた今日もハプニング
And another happening again today!
明日はどんなおかしなことが起こるかな
I wonder what kind of strange things will happen tomorrow?
ずっと隣で見ててね
Watch me from right by my side forever, okay?
みんなー！
Everyone!
今日は僕の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to my birthday live concert today!
あらためまして
Once again...
もぐもぐおかゆー！
Mogumogu Okayu!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです！
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers!
本日はこちら
Today, please use this...
ハッシュタグ #猫又おかゆ生誕祭2026 で
hashtag #NekomataOkayuSeitansai2026
いっぱい呟いてください！
and tweet a lot!
ライブ終わった後、すぐ見に行っちゃうんだからね
Because I'll go check it right after the live concert, you know!
ふふふふ
Hehehe.
そして、みんな見て？
And look, everyone?
今回のライブは「うぃあーどくっきー」というタイトルをつけました！
I titled this live concert 'Weird Cookie'!
「うぃあーど」っていうのは、「奇妙」っていう意味があるんだけど
'Weird' means 'strange' or 'peculiar'...
なんで「うぃあーど」ってつけたのかな、とか考えながらライブを見てくれると嬉しいなって思っているよ
...but I'd be happy if you watched the concert while wondering why I named it 'Weird'!
そして、見て？このステージ！
Also, look at this stage!
とっても可愛いでしょ？
It's so cute, right?
でも、可愛いだけじゃないんだよ
But it's not just cute.
ふふふふ
Hehehe.
すごいね、曲によってガラッと雰囲気変わるように作っていただいたので
It's amazing, they designed it so the atmosphere completely changes depending on the song.
そこもね、注目してみてみてください
So please pay close attention to that as well!
「えっ？」ってなるかもしれないね
You might go, 'Huh?'
ふふふふ
Hehehe.
そして、ゲストも今回も盛りだくさんでございます！
And we also have a ton of guests this time!
ワクワク、ドキドキ。いや、僕も今からなんかちゃんと...
Excited, nervous... I'm also wondering if I can do well with...
振り付けとか歌とか、いけんのかなと思いつつも...
...the choreography and singing from here on...
ふふふふ
Hehehe.
ではね、みんなと楽しく自分の誕生日をお祝いできたらなと思っております
Well then, I hope to celebrate my birthday happily with everyone!
そして最後に、最後に...
And finally, lastly...
みんなに喜んでもらえるような告知、用意してあるので
I've prepared an announcement that will make everyone happy...
ぜひ最後まで楽しんでもらえればなと思っております！
...so please enjoy it until the very end!
ふふふ、次の曲行ってみよっか
Hehehe, shall we move on to the next song?
ねえ あたし 知ってるよ きみ が ひとり
Hey, I know. I know you're alone
シてるの知ってるの知ってるよ
and doing it, I know, I know.
ビクンビクン震えてさ
Trembling and twitching,
声もダダ漏れなんだわ
your voice is leaking out, too.
正直に言っちゃえよ
Just say it honestly.
バレてるんだし言っちゃえよ
It's already exposed, so just say it.
効いてんの？
Is it working?
普通 普通 恥ずかしい？
Is it normal, normal, and embarrassing?
みんな隠しているだけ
Everyone is just hiding it.
むふー
(Muffuu)
モニタリング / 作詞・作曲：DECO*27
Monitoring / Lyrics & Composition: DECO*27
ねえ あたし 知ってるよ
Hey, I know.
きみがひとり 涙してるの
I know you're alone and crying,
知ってるよ
I know.
グスングスン凹んでさ
Sobbing, sobbing, you're depressed,
弱音ヒトカラ in the night
complaining to yourself in the night.
朝が来るまで一緒コース
We'll stay together until morning.
もっと泣いたって
Even if you cry more,
何度だって受け止めてあげる
I'll accept it no matter how many times.
もう我慢しないで
Don't hold it in anymore,
いっぱい出してね
let it all out.
mwah!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
慰めさせて シェイク シェイク
Let me comfort you, shake shake,
愛の才能で
with the talent of love.
泣いてくれなきゃ
If you don't cry for me,
涸れてしまう 濡れていたい
I'll dry up. I want to be wet.
ねえ いいでしょう？
Hey, that's fine, right?
舐め取って飲み干したいんだってば
I want to lick it up and drink it dry.
だっだっだってば
D-d-d-do it!
mwah!
お願い きみが欲しいの
Please, I want you.
頼り散らして シックラブ
Rely on me, sick love,
なんて最高ね
isn't it the best?
見たい見たい見たい見たい...
I want to see, I want to see, I want to see...
ねえあたし知ってるよ キミがひとり悔しがってるの 知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're regretting all alone, I know it.
ズキュンズキュンと高まるじゃん キミを推すことはやめない
My heart is throbbing wildly, right? I won't stop supporting you.
ねえあたし知ってるよ キミはできること 知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you can do it, I know it.
辛いときは弱いぐらいでちょうどいい あたしそれでも好きだよ
When times are tough, it's okay to be a little weak. I still love you anyway.
MWAH! お願いキミが欲しいの 名前を呼んでよ
Mwah! Please, I want you. Call my name.
いつだって愛に参上 キミはひとりだ
I'll always show up for love. You are all alone.
だから歌う ひとりじゃない もういいでしょう
So I sing, you're not alone, isn't that enough?
ソロプレイはおしまいなんだ たったったってば
Solo play is over now, I'm telling you.
キミが病めるときも あたしそばにいるわ
Even when you are sick, I will be by your side.
いつも見守っているわ
I am always watching over you.
そうよ 怖くないのよ
Yes, it is not scary at all.
MWAH! お願いキミが欲しいの 慰めさせて
Mwah! Please, I want you. Let me comfort you.
シェイク シェイク 愛の才能で 泣いてくれなきゃ
Shake shake, with the talent of love, if you don't cry...
枯れてしまう 触れていたい ねえいいでしょう
...I'll wither away. I want to touch you, hey, isn't that okay?
涙拭き取って 飲み干したいんだ たったったってば
I want to wipe away your tears and drink them up, I'm telling you.
MWAH! お願いキミが欲しいの 頼り散らして
Mwah! Please, I want you. Rely on me completely.
シェイプアップなんて最高ね
Shaping up is the absolute best, isn't it?
分けてくれなきゃ キミの痛い 感じてたい
If you don't share it with me, I want to feel your pain...
吸い取って 救いたいんだ たったったってば
...I want to suck it up and save you, I'm telling you.
ねえあたし知ってるよ キミがひとり涙知ってるの 知ってるよ
Hey, I know. I know you're crying all alone, I know it.
グズグズへこんでさ 弱音吐いたらインザナイト
Feeling down and whimpering, if you let out your complaints in the night...
朝が来るまで一足二足 もっと泣いたって Mommy
Step by step until morning comes, even if you cry more...
何度だって受け止めてあげる もう我慢しないで出して たったったってば
...I'll accept you over and over. Don't hold back anymore, let it out, I'm telling you.
堕 堕 堕 堕 堕 堕 堕 堕 堕
Da da da da da da da da da...
ながらの優等生 今宵も自分と密会です しんどいわ しんどいわ あー つらつら合掌
I'm an honor student, secretly meeting myself tonight. It's exhausting, it's exhausting, ah, offering a prayer.
ほんとは劣等生 あたしはあたしに説教です しんどいわ しんどいわ もーいやいや絶交
Actually, I'm a failure, preaching to myself. It's exhausting, it's exhausting, I give up, I'm breaking up with myself.
心配無用 心配無用 これは笑えるジョークソング
Don't worry, don't worry, this is just a funny joke song.
新米も老害も みんな歌えるポップソング
Newcomers and veterans alike can sing this pop song.
まあまあ それ噂っすよ ただの紙切れっすよ
Well, that's just a rumor, just a worthless piece of paper.
いいから はやく ハンコ押せや
Just hurry up and sign the contract.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん 悪魔ほどそう言うもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil, that's just what devils say.
あー 死んじゃった 死んじゃった 愛してほしいじゃん
Ah, I died, I died, I want you to love me.
それでもハマっちゃうなら それでも恋しちゃうなら
Even so, if you fall for it, even so, if you fall in love.
あー 死んじゃった 死んじゃった エンジェルエンジェル
Ah, I died, I died, Angel, Angel.
わー！悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報
Woah! Tragic news, tragic news, tragic news, tragic news.
わー！汚いね
Woah! It's dirty.
わー！飛べないね
Woah! It can't fly.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil.
あー 死んじゃった 死んじゃった
Ah, I died, I died.
本当の天使 スルーしてご臨終
Ignoring the real angel, it's the end.
あくまで天使じゃん？ 最強じゃん
After all, an angel, right? Isn't it the strongest?
堕 堕 堕 堕 堕 堕 堕 堕 堕
Da da da da da da da da da...
いいよ黙って銘々の悪意
Fine, just shut up, the malice of each of us...
夢叶うって奪ったサラリー
...stealing our salaries under the guise of "making dreams come true."
あー中毒性の高いもんには 裏があるんだな ああ
Ah, highly addictive things always have a catch, ah.
魂の枯れちゃって 嫌ね 嫌ね
Withered soul, how unpleasant, how unpleasant.
光り輝く輪っかで この首が締まってく
With this shining halo, my neck is being strangled.
嘘をつきは緩んでく 言えないS.O.S
If I tell lies, it loosens. I can't say S.O.S.
白いペンキを塗りましょう なりきってしまいましょう
Let's paint it white. Let's pretend completely.
嘘をつけば楽になる ほらやっちゃって
If you lie, it gets easier. Look, go ahead and do it.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil.
あー 死んじゃった 死んじゃった あー
Ah, I died, I died, ah.
それでも穿っちゃうけど それでも嫌っちゃうけど
Even so, we doubt it, even so, we hate it.
なりきって笑顔で エンジェルエンジェル
Pretend with a smile, Angel, Angel.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん 悪魔ほどそう言うもん
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil, that's just what devils say.
あー 死んじゃった 死んじゃった 愛してほしいじゃん
Ah, I died, I died, I want you to love me.
それでもハマっちゃうなら それでも恋しちゃうなら
Even so, if you fall for it, even so, if you fall in love.
あー 死んじゃった 死んじゃった エンジェルエンジェル
Ah, I died, I died, Angel, Angel.
わー！悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報
Woah! Tragic news, tragic news, tragic news, tragic news.
わー！汚いね
Woah! It's dirty.
わー！飛べないね
Woah! It can't fly.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん あー 死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil, ah, I died, I died.
本当の天使 スルーしてご臨終
Ignoring the real angel, it's the end.
わー！悲報 悲報 悲報 悲報
Woah! Tragic news, tragic news, tragic news, tragic news.
わー！醜いね
Woah! It's ugly.
わー！映えないね
Woah! It doesn't look good.
デビルじゃない デビルじゃないもん あー 死んじゃった 死んじゃった
I'm not a devil, I'm not a devil, ah, I died, I died.
本当の悪魔になってもプレイヤーズ
Even if I become a real devil, players...
あくまで天使じゃん？ 最強じゃん
After all, an angel, right? Isn't it the strongest?
充電器を貸して！ またあなたのせいで あたしすり減った
Lend me your charger! Once again, you've worn me out.
終電見逃して またあたしのせいで 帰れなくなった
Missed the last train, again because of me, you couldn't go home.
消耗戦に持ち込んで
Dragging it out into a war of attrition,
お互いに足を引っ張り合う
we drag each other down.
沈殿した思い出で ずっといっしょ
With our settled memories, we'll be together forever.
参観日にだって 誰からも見られていない気がしたんだ
Even on parent-teacher day, I felt like nobody was looking at me.
散々死に買って 自分の街に期待しないようにしたんだ
Suffering time after time, I tried not to expect anything from my own town.
そうやって守った孤独さえ めちゃくちゃになった
Even the loneliness I protected that way was torn to pieces.
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない こんな顔だいじにしたいと思えないもん
I've always wanted to die, I can't help it. I can't cherish a face like this.
共に過ごした日々が
If the days we spent together,
細やかな幸せが かけがえのないトラウマになってたらいいな
and our humble happiness, became an irreplaceable trauma, that would be nice.
はなればなれなんて 誰かが吐かせたバグだよね
Being separated is just a bug someone made us spit up, isn't it?
あなたの一生の後悔として 添い遂げるよ
I will stay with you forever as your lifelong regret.
大切なものってなに？ 今失くしたそれ...
What is the most important thing? That thing you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ 取り返しがつかないね
You made a mistake with me, and now it's irreversible.
健やかなるときも 病めるときも 黒い履歴の中で ずっといっしょ
In sickness and in health, we'll be together forever inside our dark history.
もうちょっと普通に 悲しいこと悲しいと思いたかった
I wanted to feel sad about sad things in a slightly more normal way.
長調のチューンに 感情委託して楽になりたかった
I wanted to outsource my feelings to a major-key tune to make things easier.
せいぜい一生懸命に 生きてくださいね
Please live your life as hard as you can.
あたしいつだって死にたくて仕方ない あんな歌の言いなりになっていたくないの
I've always wanted to die, I can't help it. I don't want to be at the beck and call of a song like that.
あなただけひとりで あたしの目を盗んで 幸せになろうなんて思わないで
Don't think you can sneak away and find happiness all by yourself.
髪を乾かしてくれた夜から あたしは壊されたんだよ
Ever since the night you dried my hair, I've been broken.
あなたの一生の後悔として 添い遂げるよ
I will stay with you forever as your lifelong regret.
外れなくなってしまった指輪みたいに
Like a ring that got stuck and won't come off,
何度もずっとフラッシュバックしている 裂いて痛いよ
it keeps flashing back over and over. It hurts to be torn apart.
一緒に居た時の方が あたし可愛かったなぁ
I was much cuter when we were together.
あなたの一生の後悔として 添い遂げるよ
I will stay with you forever as your lifelong regret.
大切なものってなに？ 今失くしたそれ...
What is the most important thing? That thing you just lost.
あたしと間違いを犯しちゃったんだ 取り返しがつかないね
You made a mistake with me, and now it's irreversible.
健やかなるときも 病めるときも ほかの誰かと眠っていても お揃いの悪夢で ずっといっしょ
In sickness and in health, even if you are sleeping with someone else, we'll be together forever in matching nightmares.
愛♡スクリーム！
[On-Screen: Love Scream!]
教えて！もっと あなたの事
Tell me! More about you!
Tell me! もっもっもっもっ Tell me!
Tell me! Mo-mo-mo-more, tell me!
聞かせて！もっと あなたの声
Let me hear! More of your voice!
Let me hear! もっもっもっもっ Let me hear!
Let me hear! Mo-mo-mo-more, let me hear!
こんなドキドキ もう抑えきれない
I can't contain this throbbing heart anymore!
All I need you, All I need you
All I need is you, all I need is you!
友達は卒業 運命の私 見つけてほしいの
No longer friends, I want you to find the 'me' of destiny.
1! 勇気を出して
One! Gather up your courage!
2! 見つめる作戦
Two! Operation: Staring at you!
3! 目と目が合えば
Three! Once our eyes meet,
4! 止められない!
Four! You can't stop it!
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! この恋 この愛で メルティ 溶けちゃうよ
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! With this love, this affection, I'll melt away!
ねぇ？ ねえ、ねえ、ねえ、気づいて my darling 届け！ 大好き！
Hey? Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling! Reach out! I love you!
愛！ スクリーム！ スクリーム！ 叫びましょう！
Love! Scream! Scream! Let's shout it out!
スクリーム！ アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice cream!
愛！ スクリーム！ スクリーム！ 叫びましょう！
Love! Scream! Scream! Let's shout it out!
スクリーム！ アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice cream!
ルーナちゃん！ はい！ 何が好き？
Luna-chan! Yes! What do you like?
チョコミントよりも あなた！
Even more than chocolate mint, I like you!
わためちゃん！ はい！ 何が好き？
Watame-chan! Yes! What do you like?
ストロベリーフレーバーよりも あなた！
Even more than strawberry flavor, I like you!
おかゆちゃん！ はい！ 何が好き？
Okayu-chan! Yes! What do you like?
クッキー＆クリームよりも あなた！
Even more than cookies and cream, I like you!
みんな！ はい！ 何が好き？
Everyone! Yes! What do you like?
もちろん大好き アイスクリーム！
Of course, I love ice cream!
止められない！
I can't stop it!
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! この恋 この愛で メルティ 溶けちゃうよ
Yeah! Yeah! Yeah! With this love, this affection, I'll melt away!
ねぇ？ ねえ、ねえ、ねえ、気づいて my darling 届け！ 大好き！
Hey? Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling! Reach out! I love you!
愛！ スクリーム！ スクリーム！ 叫びましょう！
Love! Scream! Scream! Let's shout it out!
スクリーム！ アイスクリーム！
Scream! Ice cream!
愛！ スクリーム！ スクリーム！ 叫びましょう！
Love! Scream! Scream! Let's shout it out!
叫びましょう
Let's scream!
スクリーム! アイスクリーム!
Scream! Ice cream!
おねがい 見つけて マイダーリン
Please find me, my darling!
おねがい 気づいて マイダーリン
Please notice me, my darling!
勇気を出して
Summon your courage,
近づく作戦
and start the approach strategy!
手と手が触れて
Our hands touch...
止められない
...and I can't stop it!
Yeah yeah yeah この恋 この愛で
Yeah, yeah, yeah, with this love and affection,
Melty とけちゃうよ
I'm melting away!
ねえ ねえ ねえ 気づいて マイダーリン
Hey, hey, hey, notice me, my darling!
それは あなた
That's you!
アイ・スクリーム! スクリーム! 叫びましょう
Love ♡ Scream! Scream! Let's scream!
スクリーム! アイスクリーム!
Scream! Ice cream!
アイ・スクリーム! スクリーム! 叫びましょう
Love ♡ Scream! Scream! Let's scream!
スクリーム! アイスクリーム!
Scream! Ice cream!
アイ・スクリーム! スクリーム! 叫びましょう
Love ♡ Scream! Scream! Let's scream!
スクリーム! アイスクリーム!
Scream! Ice cream!
アイ・スクリーム! スクリーム! 叫びましょう
Love ♡ Scream! Scream! Let's scream!
スクリーム! アイスクリーム!
Scream! Ice cream!
La la la...
魔法みたいな 夢みたいな ファンタジックな物語が
A magical, dream-like, fantastic story...
世界に感染 愉快に蔓延 待って そんなの聞いてないってば
...infects the world, spreading delightfully! Wait, I didn't hear about that!
ポンポン的に 痛い 異常 行動 支える 枯れない 脳、総量
Fundamentally, painful abnormal behavior, supporting the unwithering total brain capacity.
本能的に 深い 破壊 衝動 照らす 確かな 改像度
Instinctively, deep destructive impulses, illuminating a clear resolution.
恋の導火線
The fuse of love...
いざ、火灯し、ひとつ、ここらで本調子
...is lit! Let's get into top gear!
脳細胞に今叩き込め
Hammer it into your brain cells right now,
わからないことだらけを
all these things you don't understand!
あざとい、際どい、笑わないで
Calculated, risky, please don't laugh.
いつも いつも ごまかしては ダーリン
You're always, always dodging it, Darling.
要らない 知らない おだてないで
I don't need it, I don't know, don't flatter me.
言えない 消えない 思い込め
Unspeakable, unforgettable, pouring my feelings in...
愛の強制ミューティレーション!
...love's forced mutilation!
魔法みたいな 夢みたいな 世界に感染 愉快に蔓延
A magical, dream-like story, infecting the world, spreading delightfully!
待って こんなの聞いてないって、ダーリン?
Wait, I didn't hear about that, Darling?
ベターな恋愛 エラーな展開 だって それじゃあつまらないでしょ
A better romance, an error-prone progression, because otherwise it'd be boring, right?
切り抜けて 引き付けて 愛の仮面 ストレート
Cut through it, attract it, with a straightforward mask of love!
根本的に マズい 胃腸 行動 支える イカれた 情報量
Fundamentally bad gastrointestinal behavior, supporting a crazy amount of information.
圧倒的に 淡い 母性 本能 暴く 飢えた 奴隷根性
Overwhelmingly faint maternal instinct, exposing a starved slave mentality.
愛の導火線
The fuse of love...
いざ 火を点けて 頭の中はアルデンテ
...is lit! My head is totally al dente!
性細胞に今流し込め
Pour it into my germ cells right now,
耐え難いことだらけを
all these unbearable things!
冷たい触れ合い 遊ばないで
Cold physical contact, please don't play with me.
いつも いつも 当てつけては ダーリン
You're always, always taking it out on me, Darling.
拙い うかがい ふざけないで
A clumsy inquiry, don't mess around with me.
言えない 消えない 思い込め
Unspeakable, unforgettable, pouring my feelings in...
愛の執念、アイスピック!
...love's obsession, an icepick!
好きな人の 好きな人 ってだけで 嫌い
I hate them just because they're the one my beloved loves.
都合の良い子 演じて一生 終わりたくないんだよ
I don't want to spend my whole life acting like a convenient girl.
狂った未来に戯画を 終わった抵抗 いっそこのまま目を塞いで
A caricature in a crazy future, an ended resistance, might as well close my eyes like this.
切って、爽快 喰らって、崩壊 知って、後悔 望んだ将来
Cut and feel refreshed, consume and collapse, know and regret, the future I desired.
手を繋いで
Hold hands,
場を繋いで
buy some time,
ファンタジックなすったもんだが
a fantastic, chaotic mess...
積もりに感染
...infects our accumulated mess,
危険に発展
...developing into a danger!
...も聞いてないって ダーリン
...You're not even listening, darling.
ベターな恋愛 エラーな展開
A better love, an error of a development.
だってそれじゃつまんないでしょう
Because that's just boring, isn't it?
踏みつけて 焼き付けて
Step on me, burn it in...
とろけそうな 酸素神経
My oxygen nerves are about to melt.
壊れそうな 群本能
My herd instinct is about to break.
崩れそうな 情を前に
Faced with feelings about to collapse...
愛の脳内レボリューション
An intracerebral revolution of love!
ドッキドキメキ 気流に私は乗っている
With a pounding heartbeat, I'm riding on the airflow!
きっとね
Surely.
なんか 言葉にできない こと
Something I can't put into words,
ちょっと 心の臓 騒がす こと
something that makes my heart flutter,
なんとなく 今日を照らす こと
something that vaguely lights up today...
ちょっと 好みの花 見つけた！
I found a flower I like!
白い霧 ばかり エブリデイ
Every day is just filled with white fog,
探したいものさえ 探せないよ
I can't even find what I'm looking for.
わくわくした そうな ダイアリー
An exciting-looking diary,
知らんぷりして 放り出すなんて
to just pretend not to know and throw it away...
ライヤイヤイヤイヤ
La-iya-iya-iya...
やるせなかった ハート
My helpless heart.
Wow wow wow wow
Wow, wow...
「でも、だけど」から「きっと、可能性あり」
From "but, still" to "surely, there's a possibility!"
気持ちいい風に 浮遊して
Floating in a pleasant breeze,
うんと すっと ちょっともっと いつかは飛べたらいいな！
someday, a little more, I hope I can fly!
ドッキドキメキ 気流に私は乗っている
With a pounding heartbeat, I'm riding on the airflow!
きっとね
Surely,
分からない 物語に ビビらないで
don't be afraid of a story you don't understand!
キラキラ空想に 世界が踊る！
The world dances in a sparkling fantasy!
笑って
Just laugh!
縮こまってる 時間はないな
There's no time to be cowering down!
私を知りたい！
I want to know myself!
何もかもが まだ 分からない
There's still so much I don't know...
私を見つけたい！
I want to find myself!
いってきますを 声にできたなら
If I could say "I'm off!" out loud,
ちょっとだけ 大人になったかもね
maybe I've grown up just a little bit.
チャッチャカチャカ 深呼吸
Take a quick deep breath,
優しくあるたびに シッソク
stalling every time I try to be kind.
つまんない 僻地は 夢がない
A boring, lonely place has no dreams,
ちょっと 嫌いな自分 見つけた
I found a side of myself I dislike.
黒い霧 覆う エブリデイ
Every day covered in a dark fog,
雨に打たれて 帰りたくなるの
getting hit by rain makes me want to go home.
わくわくした そうな ダイアリー
An exciting-looking diary,
少し浮かれて 走り出すなんて
getting a little carried away and running off...
まあいいやイヤイヤイヤ
Well, whatever...
シャカリキでいく ハート
Go all out with this heart!
Wow wow wow wow
Wow, wow...
お気に入りのアクセは失くしたくないの
I don't want to lose my favorite accessory!
Wow wow wow wow
Wow, wow...
まだ何も分かっちゃいないんだ
I still don't understand anything yet!
Wow wow wow wow
Wow, wow...
好きって気持ちに向かいたい
I want to face my feelings of liking things!
あの星のように 輝きたい
I want to shine like that star!
Oh
ドッキドキメキ 気流に私は乗っている
With a pounding heartbeat, I'm riding on the airflow!
やっぱね
I knew it,
答えのない 世界で生きてるせいです
it's because I'm living in a world without answers.
未来は優秀にあっても変わんないし
Even if the future is great, it won't change,
叫んで
so shout it out,
私らしく体現！
expressing myself!
ドッキドキメキ 気流を乗り越えた先には
Beyond overcoming the pounding heartbeat airflow,
分からない 物物語が待っている
a story I don't know is waiting!
小さな勇気で 何かを変えよう！
Let's change something with a little courage!
Ah
ねえ、大切な話があるんだ
Hey, there's something important I have to say,
ここになく 探しものがあるんだ
there's something I'm looking for that isn't here.
だから旅に出ます
So, I'm going on a journey,
そのうち帰ります
I'll return eventually.
ちょっとだけ 大人になったかもね
Maybe I've grown up just a little bit.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明
We are all nonsense,
we are all nonsense.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明
We are all nonsense,
we are all nonsense.
夜が明ける
The night breaks,
朝目覚める
waking up in the morning.
首痛める この身体に自分がいる
My neck hurts; I am inside this body.
君と喋る
Talking with you,
飯を食べる
eating a meal,
服を着てる そのすべてが不気味である
wearing clothes—all of it is so eerie.
なんか変だ 変だ 変だ 変だ
Something is weird, weird, weird, weird!
駅の改札通り抜ける
Passing through the station ticket gate,
こんな平和 平和 平和 平和
such peace, peace, peace, peace...
当たり前で受ける
Taking it all for granted.
猫の名前は なんとなくタマで
The cat's name is somehow 'Tama',
犬の...
and the dog's is...
犬の 名前は
The dog's name is...
なんとなくポチだ
somehow Pochi.
世界は
The world,
なんとなく終わりそうで
somehow seems like it's going to end,
存在を抱えたまま 夕焼けに溶けていくよ
holding onto existence, I dissolve into the sunset.
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も ないないない無駄かもしれない
The meaning of living, the meaning of trying, none, none, none, it might be a waste.
千年後何も残らないけど それでも君と笑っていたい
Even if nothing remains after a thousand years, I still want to laugh with you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we are all meaningless.
月が昇る
The moon rises,
星が光る
the stars shine,
虫が跳ねる
the insects jump,
それを見てる
I'm watching that.
あれいつからここにいるんだっけ自白しろ
When did I start being here?
いつまでここにいられるんだっけ
How long can I stay here?
何にもなれないままで
Remaining as nothing,
化け物から逃れてるだけ
just escaping from monsters,
座敷牢でイメージを浮かべて
in a confined room, imagining things,
ストップした思考は敵だらけ
the stopped thinking is full of enemies.
太郎の名前は 今でも太郎で
Taro's name is still Taro,
次郎の名前は 今では花子だ
Jiro's name is now Hanako.
時間は
Time,
なんとなく通り過ぎて
passes by somehow,
ゴミ溜目で埋もれたまま 星空を眺めてるよ
buried in a trash dump, I'm looking at the starry sky.
愛する意味も 恋する意味も ないないない嘘かもしれない
The meaning of loving, the meaning of falling in love, none, none, none, it might be a lie.
1+1もよくわからんけど それでも君を守っていたい
One plus one, I don't know well, but I still want to protect you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we are all meaningless.
それでもぼくらはトンネルで息を止める
Even so, we stop our breath in the tunnel,
折り紙で鶴を折る
fold a paper crane,
肉球を触る
touch the paw pads,
横断歩道の白い部分だけを踏む
and step only on the white part of the crosswalk.
それでもぼくら間違ったことをする
Even so, we do wrong things,
正しいと思い込む
convince ourselves it is correct.
頭いいからわかっていた
Because we're smart, we understood.
またわかった気になっていたんだ
Pretending we understood again.
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も ないないない ないないない
The meaning of living, the meaning of trying, none, none, none, none, none, none,
ないないない ないないない
none, none, none, none, none, none.
それでもやるしかない
Even so, we just have to do it!
生きてる意味も 頑張る意味も ないないない無駄かもしれない
The meaning of living, the meaning of trying, none, none, none, it might be a waste.
千年後何ものこらないけど それでも君と笑っていたい
Even if nothing remains after a thousand years, I still want to laugh with you.
夢を叶えても 悟り開いても 結局は孤独かもしれない
Even if dreams come true, or we achieve enlightenment, in the end we might be lonely.
お化けになっても 虚無に帰っても それでも君と笑っていたいな
Even if we become ghosts or return to nothingness, I still want to laugh with you.
ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Because we are all meaningless.
そう ぼくらはみんな意味不明
Yes, we are all meaningless.
そう ぼくらはみんな意味不明だから
Yes, because we are all meaningless.
そう簡単な祈りだった ハナから
Yes, it was a simple prayer from the start.
段々と消える感嘆 今から
Gradually vanishing sighs, from now on...
どん帳が上がるから
The curtain is rising, so...
静かな会場を後に さよなら
Leaving the quiet venue behind, goodbye.
言いかけていた言葉が一つ 消えてまた増えて
The words I was about to say vanished, then increased again,
背中に後ろめたさが残る
leaving a sense of guilt behind my back.
「綻ぶ前にここを出ていこうか」と
'Shall we get out of here before it unravels?' I mumble,
都合の良い願いを
that convenient wish,
同じ様に同じ様に呟く
the same way, the same way.
何処から聞こうか
Where shall we ask from?
何を見失うか
What will we lose sight of?
定かじゃないから此処を動けない
Because it's not certain, I can't move from here.
僕らが疲れるなら
If we get tired,
これ以上無いなら
if there's nothing more than this,
その度に何回も逃げ出せる様に
I hope we can escape over and over again each time.
心が守れる様に
So that my heart can be protected,
奪われない様に
so that it won't be stolen,
互いに託して身体を預けてよ Nus
let's entrust ourselves to each other and lean on each other.
らるらるら らるらるら
La lu la lu la...
らるらるら
らるらるら らるらるら
La lu la lu la...
らるらるら
君と泣く
I cry with you,
君と笑う
I laugh with you,
君と怒る
I get angry with you.
君と歌う
I sing with you,
君と踊る
I dance with you,
君と話す
I talk with you.
何時まで続くだろうと
Wondering how long this will last,
同じ様に同じ様に呟く
I mumble the same way, the same way.
いま忘れないよう刻まれた空気を
So I won't forget now, the air that was engraved,
これから何回思い出すのだろう
how many times will I recall it from now on?
僕らだけが
Only us.
僕らが離れるなら
If we are going to part,
僕らが迷うなら
if we are going to get lost,
その度に何回も繋がれる様に
I hope we can be connected over and over again each time.
ここに居てくれるなら
If you stay here,
離さず居られたら
if you don't let go of me,
まだ誰も知らない感覚で
I'll be saved by a feeling no one knows yet...
僕の生きている全てを
Check everything of my life,
確かめて 正しくして
and make it right.
Expected we are
Very expected we are
Unhappy?
悩める人の子よ
Oh troubled child of man,
Unlucky?
人成らざる者も
Even you, who are no longer human,
Be happy!
弛まず目指せよ
Don't slack off, aim for it,
Undead 生きているんだし
Undead, since you are alive after all.
目を逸らした過去も
The past you turned your eyes away from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future, too.
カウンセリング
Counseling?
やれやれ決まり事
Give me a break.
古今東西
Time and again, everywhere,
ピースピース
peace, peace.
Unhappy?
Unlucky?
Be happy!
Undead
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ なんだかどうして
Hey... why is it...
戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
I feel like I'm fighting?
触れられない 触れたくもない
I don't want to touch it, I can't touch it,
この自分 自分 自分 自分と
with my past self, self, self, self...
もうとっくに死んでる
who's already dead,
透明な亡霊と対決
confronting a transparent ghost.
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
Deep in the memories, youthful and painful.
残念 もう居ないのに
Too bad? Even though you're already gone.
あれ そっちが良いアイロニーね
Oh? You prefer that? How ironic.
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is it your present self that's being seen through?
ナンセンス
Nonsense.
消えないレッテル
An unerasable label,
いえ 要はコンプレックス
yes, the point is, it's a complex.
取り憑かれているみたい
It seems I'm possessed by it,
巻き付いたまま
still wrapped around,
まだ離れない
still won't leave...
在りし日の自分
the self of days gone by.
Undead
死んじゃいない
You're not dead.
お前とお前の連鎖
A chain of you and you.
生きていることとは変わり続けることだ
Being alive means to keep changing.
不幸に甘んじて
Don't be content with misfortune...
満足するなよ
and be satisfied with it.
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
It's cowardly not to try to become happy.
この世 この世は
This world, this world is
奇怪 奇怪 ファンタジー
a strange, strange fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
What will appear next, an ogre or a snake?
出会って遭ってやっと始まる物語
Meet, encounter, and finally the story begins.
さあ人か化物か
Come, are you human or a monster?
閑話休題
Enough with this, let's talk about something else.
ピースピース
Peace, peace.
Past & Future
Can't change the past
Run for the future
カットイン
Cut in.
なんだかどうして
Why is it...
未来になんぞ
that for the future...
何の希望もない 期待出来ない
I have no hope, no expectations?
ような気がして
I feel like that.
もう随分生きている
I've been alive for a long time,
既視感とテンプレで食傷
sick of the déjà vu and the templates.
素敵な出来事の気配もない
There's not even a sign of a wonderful event.
残念
Too bad.
積んだ経験の因果
The cause and effect of the experience I've piled up,
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
mythology that has become a shell, and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
The point is, I want stimulation.
飽きちゃった
I'm tired of it.
慣れちゃった
I'm used to it.
なんて
And so...
整っていくガイダンス
The guidance that keeps setting me up,
増えるコンプライアンス
increasing compliance...
蓋されていくみたい
It feels like it's being covered up.
吸い尽くして
Suck it all up.
あれも これも どれも onions
All of it, all of it, all of it,
同じ味がする
it all tastes the same.
Undead
死んじゃいない
You're not dead.
お前とお前の連鎖
A chain of you and you.
何時の世も 過去も未来も現在にあるんだ
In every age, the past, the future, and the present are all here.
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill the act of being alive honestly.
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending.
Undead
死んじゃいない_お前に
You're not dead.
お前に言っているんだ
I'm telling you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな
Don't give up on happiness.
人で在れ
Be human.
ただ苦しみに慣れて耐えているだけじゃ
If you're just used to suffering and enduring it,
死んでいるも同然
you're as good as dead.
屍のアンデッド
A corpse, an undead.
Unhappy?
悩める人の子よ
Oh troubled child of man,
Unlucky?
人成らざる者も
Even you, who are no longer human,
Be happy!
弛まず目指せよ
Don't slack off, aim for it,
Undead 生きているんだろ
Undead, since you are alive.
不幸に浸るも
Whether you soak in misfortune
幸せになるのも_そう全部
or become happy...
そう全部全部お前だ
Yeah, it's all, all on you.
古今東西
Time and again, everywhere,
一切合切
everything, everything,
森羅万象
all things in nature.
ピースピース
Peace, peace.
Past & Future
Can't change the past
Run for the future
人の在る所に何時も憂い事
Wherever there are people, there is always sorrow.
生き抜けこの化物ばかりの物語
Survive this story full of monsters.
悪魔の踊り方
[Title: Devil's Manner]
感情なんてもんはどうしても無駄だって悪魔は言った
"Things like emotions are useless no matter what," so said the devil.
「何もかも捨てちまえよ」
"Just throw away everything!"
嗚呼、快不快も、喜怒哀楽さえも！
Ah, pleasure and displeasure, even your human emotions!
どうしようもない事実、ヒトは終焉から逃れられない
It's an inescapable truth, humans can't run away from their demise.
「誰も抗えない欲望に従え」
"Obey the desires that no one can resist."
思考を休めるな 脳ミソを回せ
Don't rest your mind, put those brains to action.
「誰もお前のことなど見ちゃいないさ」
"No one is watching you or anything..."
おかしくなってしまうことをどうして恥じる？
Why are you embarrassed of becoming a bit strange?
お前らに
To you all...
完璧で間違った踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you all a perfect but mistaken way to dance,
いっせーので捨てちまえ、そんな命ならば
so if it's that kind of life, throw it away on "Ready, set, go!"
何十何百何千何万回学習しなさいな
Learn it tens, hundreds, thousands, millions of times.
どうしたってさ、空っぽの頭蓋骨だろ
At any rate, your skull is empty.
わかっているのかい？
You understand that, right?
感情なんていつ何時でも邪魔だって悪魔は言った
"Emotions are a nuisance every moment of your life," so said the devil.
「反論の余地などない」
"There's no room for objections."
嗚呼、人生に意味を与えておくれ！
Ah, grant meaning upon this human life!
420でさえも救えない終焉があると知った
I knew that there's a demise that not even 420 could save me from.
「誰も疑わない神様を疑え」
"Doubt the god that no one else questions."
思考を休めるな 脳ミソを回せ
Don't rest your mind, put those brains to action.
「誰もお前のことなど見ちゃいないさ」
"No one is watching you or anything..."
躊躇っている数秒の無益さを知れ
Know of the futility of your few seconds of hesitation.
お前らに
To you all...
完璧で間違った踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you all a perfect but mistaken way to dance,
いっせーので捨てちまえ、そんな命ならば
so if it's that kind of life, throw it away on "Ready, set, go!"
何十何百何千何万回学習しなさいな
Learn it tens, hundreds, thousands, millions of times.
どうしたってさ、頭ん中空っぽなこと
At any rate, the inside of your head is empty.
わかっていないようだ
And it seems you don't understand that.
承認欲にレイプされ、死んだ花をぶら下げている女
A woman, hanging up dead flowers, raped by her want of recognition.
何かを愛すことすら、ままならないまま餌を待つだけ
Without even having anything to love, she waits for her feed without having her way.
踊り方を知らない、芸術の価値などわからないやつらに
For those who don't know how to dance, who don't understand the value of art,
堕落していれば 何も見えないまま
if they fall into depravity, they'll see nothing at all.
真善美に背いた踊り方を教えてやるから
I'll teach you a dance that goes against truth, goodness, and beauty,
いっせーので狂っちまえ、惨めな姿で
so in your miserable state, just go mad on "Ready, set, go!"
何十何百何千何万何億人の中でさぁ
In the midst of those tens, hundreds, thousands, millions, billions of people,
そうして埋もれていたっていいと どうして言えるのだろう？
why can you say that you are fine with being buried?
ねえ
Hey,
世界が患っている狂信は
the fanaticism that this world is afflicted with
健常者でさえ目が眩むような光を放っている
lets out a light that makes even a healthy person dizzy.
今夜、悪魔がお前らにこう云うぜ
Tonight, the devil will speak to you as such:
「神とやらに惑わされるなよ」
"Don't let yourself be led astray by some god."
はーい！
Okay!
「悪魔の踊り方」歌わせていただきました！
I sang "Akuma no Odorikata"!
いや、「悪魔の踊り方」ってさ、すごいカッコいい曲じゃない？
I mean, "Akuma no Odorikata" is such a cool song, isn't it?
ああいうカッコいい歌うたうと、なんかちゃんと
When I sing cool songs like that,
様になっているのかなって
I wonder if I'm pulling it off well,
なんか心細い気持ちに実はなってるんだよね。
and I actually end up feeling a bit anxious.
ちゃんとカッコよく歌えてたかな、僕？
Did I manage to sing it coolly?
はい、ということでね
Right, and so...
なんかもう、ここまであっという間だったよね。
it really feels like it's been in the blink of an eye up to this point.
もうこんな時間経ってるんだっていう感じでございますが。
It really feels like, "Wow, has that much time passed already?"
なんとですね、ここから告知タイムとさせていただきます！
But guess what, from here on, we're going to have an announcement time!
はい、です。
Here I am!
はぁ...
*pant*
まずは、みんなに見ていただきたいCMがございます。
First, there is a commercial I would like everyone to see.
あ、やばい。みんな、心して？
Oh, my god. Everyone, are you ready?
どうぞ！
Here you go!
ここからは檜山修之が、猫又おかゆ誕生日記念グッズ2026のグッズをご紹介するぞ！
From here, Hiyama Nobuyuki will introduce the Nekomata Okayu Birthday Celebration 2026 Merchandise!
まずはこれだ！
First up is this!
はっぴ〜 おかゆはっぴ！
Happy Okayu Happi!
神岡ちろる先生の描き下ろしイラストが描かれた法被がグッズになったぞ！
The happi featuring a newly drawn illustration by Kamioka Chiroru-sensei is now merchandise!
きょとん顔のおかゆんがとてもキュート！
Okayun's blank stare is super cute!
イベントやライブに着ていけば、一目で おにぎりゃー アピールできる、スーパーハッピーなグッズだ！
If you wear it to events or concerts, you can show you are an Onigiriya at a glance. It's a super happy item!
お出かけに連れてって、アクリルスタンド！
Take me out with you, Acrylic Stand!
アクスタはもう家に飾るだけの時代じゃない！
The era of acrylic stands just sitting at home is over!
日々のお出かけを彩る、推し活マストアイテム。
A must-have fan item to color your daily outings.
ポーチに入れて外に持ち運んで、おかゆんに世界をたくさん見せてあげてくれよな！
Put it in a pouch, take it outside, and show Okayun plenty of the world!
ごくごく！BIGたんぶら〜！
Gulp, gulp! BIG Tumbler!
甘城なつき先生描き下ろしのミニキャラが描かれた大容量のタンブラー。
A large-capacity tumbler featuring a mini-character newly drawn by Amashiro Natsuki-sensei.
持ち手やストローもついているので、外出時はもちろん、勉強中や仕事中、様々なシチュエーションで大活躍間違いなし！
With a handle and a straw included, it's perfect for outings, studying, or working in various situations!
おかゆんの配信を見る時にも使ってくれ！
Use it when you watch Okayun's streams, too!
おでかけおにぎり型、ショルダーポーチ！
Outing Onigiri-shaped Shoulder Pouch!
アクスタやhololive friends to Goなど、ちっとした小物が入る優れたショルダーポーチだぜ！
An excellent shoulder pouch that fits small items like acrylic stands and hololive friends to Go!
透明素材なので、日々の推し活に使える一品となっているぞ！
Since it's made of transparent material, it's perfect for your daily fan activities!
そして！
And next...
フルセット購入特典はこちら！
The full set purchase bonus is here!
なんと、フルセットを購入した全員に、猫又おかゆ直筆サイン＆複製メッセージ入りポストカードがついてくる！
Incredibly, everyone who purchases the full set will receive a postcard with Nekomata Okayu's hand-written signature and printed message!
おにぎりゃーのみんな、絶対ゲットしてくれよな！
Every Onigiriya, make sure to get it!
ひゃっほーい！
Yippee!
はぁ...
*pant*
ということで、あの、檜山修之さんに、生誕グッズのCMを録っていただきました！やばい！
And with that, Hiyama Nobuyuki-san has recorded the commercial for my birthday merchandise! It's crazy!
檜山修之さんというね、あの、レジェンドの声優さんがいらっしゃいまして、
There is this legendary voice actor named Hiyama Nobuyuki-san,
猫又おかゆ、ホロライブデビュー時からの、世界で一番大好きな声優さんとなっております！
and he has been Nekomata Okayu's number one favorite voice actor in the world since my Hololive debut!
あの、この場をお借りして、あの、檜山修之さん本当にありがとうございました！
I'd like to take this opportunity to say... Hiyama Nobuyuki-san, thank you so much!
はぁ、はぁ...
*pant*
ちょっと興奮冷めやらぬなんですが、
I'm still incredibly excited,
あの、CMにあった通り、猫又おかゆ生誕グッズ2026を発売させていただきますので、
but as shown in the commercial, Nekomata Okayu Birthday Celebration 2026 Merchandise is now on sale,
皆さんぜひご予約お待ちしてます！
so everyone, please make your reservations!
そして、告知は1つだけじゃないんですね！
And that's not the only announcement!
続きまして、こちら！どうぞ！
Next up is this! Here it is!
いよいよお待たせ、来月3月26日木曜日に「おかゆにゅ〜む R」
Finally, the wait is over. Next month, on Thursday, March 26th, "Okayunyuumu R"
あ、ん？アール！
Ah, huh? R!
ん？アール！
Huh? R!
「おかゆにゅ〜む R」がリリース！
"Okayunyuumu R" will be released!
青森を舞台に、君と2人で商品開発という名の、恋人旅行がスタート？
Set in Aomori, a lover's trip under the guise of product development with you begins?
笑いあり、デートあり、野球拳もあり！
With laughter, dates, and even yakyuken!
の、盛りだくさんな作品となっております。
It's a content-packed game.
自分で、自分でさ、
I can't believe...
「野球拳ありって何？」って思っちゃったね、うん。
...I just wondered to myself, "What do you mean, yakyuken?"
自分で言ったくせにね、
Even though I'm the one who said it.
僕が野球拳ありたいって言ったくせにね！
Even though I was the one who insisted on adding yakyuken!
そして、
And,
「野球拳あるのに、CERO Cは大丈夫なのかよ？」というお声、度々いただいておりますが、
I've often heard people ask, "Is CERO C really okay with yakyuken?"
なんと心配していたCERO審査も無事、「C」で決まりました！
But miraculously, the CERO rating we worried about has been approved as "C"!
ふー、よかったよかった！
Phew, thank goodness!
うーん、そして、みんな体験版ももう既に遊んでくれたかな？
Well, has everyone played the demo version yet?
あのドキドキの続きは、ぜひ君の目で確かめてほしいな！
I hope you will see what happens next after that heart-pounding moment with your own eyes!
まだまだたくさんの未公開情報もあるとのことなので、おかゆにゅ〜む Rから目が離せないよ！
There's still plenty of unreleased information, so keep your eyes on "Okayunyuumu R"!
ぜひお楽しみに！
Please look forward to it!
そして、こちら、最後の告知となります！
And this will be the final announcement!
毎年発表させていただいているんですが、今日もライブの最後に新曲を発表させていただきます！
I announce one every year, but today, at the end of the concert, I'm announcing a new song!
はぁ、やっと言えた！
Phew, I finally said it!
今回はですね、てにをはさんに作詞作曲をしていただきました！
This time, Teniwoha-san wrote and composed it for me!
ありがとうございました、てにをはさん！
Thank you so much, Teniwoha-san!
でわでわ、あの、色々言いたいこととかもあるんですが、
Well then, well, there are various things I want to say, but...
まずはキミの目でしっかりと聴いていただければなと、見ていただければなと思っております。
first, I hope you'll listen carefully... I mean, watch closely with your own eyes.
でわでわ、
Well then...
聴いてください。「ノンデリシャス」
Please listen. 'Non-Delicious'
今日も噛む噛むワンツースリー
Today again, chew chew, one, two, three
舌も踊るよワンツースリー
The tongue dances too, one, two, three
トラウマをじっくり煮込んだボルシチどうぞ
Here is some borscht, made by simmering trauma slowly
キミの心臓は歯型だらけさ
Your heart is covered in teeth marks
苦肉のステーキとセルフィッシュ＆チップス
Desperate measure steak and selfish & chips
マンネリを刻んだサラダ
A salad with chopped-up ruts
こんなにも美味しい食卓 邪魔しないで
Don't interrupt such a delicious dining table
お口を開けて はい あーん
Open your mouth, go 'ahh'
ウェイター ウェイター お皿下げないで
Waiter, waiter, don't take the plates away
これがボクの美味しいものなんだから
Because this is my delicious meal
ハングリー ロンリー グラトニー 新しいメニュー
Hungry, lonely, gluttony, a new menu
みんなクワイエット クワイエット お待ちかね
Everyone quiet, quiet, it's what you've been waiting for
デ デ デ デ デリシャス デリ デリシャス
De-de-de-de-delicious, deli-delicious
ノン デ デ デ デ デリシャス デリ デリシャス
Non-de-de-de-de-delicious, deli-delicious
そんなテリブル テーブル 蹴っ飛ばして
Kick away such a terrible table
エブリデイ エブリナイト がっつかないで
Everyday, every night, don't devour it greedily
ノンデリシャス なんべんだってオカワリ
Non-delicious, seconds as many times as you want
おえっ
Ugh
お皿積む 積み上げ 3, 4, 5
Piling up the plates, three, four, five
バベルみたいに 3, 4, 5
Like the Tower of Babel, three, four, five
喉の奥につっかえて窒息しかけても
Even if it gets stuck in the throat and almost chokes me
大人は飲み込むらしい すっごいね
Apparently adults just swallow it, how amazing
見栄と意地のソテー 義理人情サンドイッチ
Sauteed vanity and stubbornness, duty and humanity sandwich
情熱の冷めたスープ
A soup where passion has cooled down
そんなもの頼んでないから
Since I didn't order anything like that
ボクはボクで好きなものだけ食べるだけ
I'll just eat only what I like, my way
ウェイター ウェイター 際限なくもっと持ってきて
Waiter, waiter, bring more without limit
これがボクの美味しい日々なんだから
Because this is my delicious daily life
異論 反論 もろもろ 飲み込んだあとで
After swallowing objections, refutations, and everything else
挑め ダイエット ダイエット
Challenge your diet, diet
一心不乱に 噛む 噛む 不条理を噛む
Intently chew, chew, chew the absurdity
のらりくらり幸せそうな顔して
Dodging and slacking with a happy face
噛む 噛む あくまで噛む
Chew, chew, chew to the very end
みんなクワイエット クワイエット お待ちかね
Everyone quiet, quiet, it's what you've been waiting for
デ デ デ デ デリシャス デリ デリシャス
De-de-de-de-delicious, deli-delicious
ノン デ デ デ デ デリシャス デリ デリシャス
Non-de-de-de-de-delicious, deli-delicious
そんなテリブル テーブル 蹴っ飛ばして
Kick away such a terrible table
エブリデイ エブリナイト がっつかないで
Everyday, every night, don't devour it greedily
ノンデリシャス でもなんべんだってオカワリしよう
Non-delicious, but let's get seconds as many times as we want
おにぎりゃー！！ 今日はお祝いしてくれてほんとにありがとう ＞ｍ＜ ♡
Onigiryas!! Thank you so much for celebrating with me today ＞ｍ＜ ♡
毎日がハッピーなのも、皆のおかげ ♡ ずっっっと一緒にいようね ☆
My everyday being happy is all thanks to everyone ♡ Let's stay together forever and ever ☆
ちょっとでも、君の究極のきっかけになれますように... 猫又おかゆ
I hope I can be even a tiny spark of your ultimate motivation... — Nekomata Okayu